Go back to the day that Anne was waiting at the train station...
Anne of Green Gables is a family, drama film directed by Kevin Sullivan.
At the turn of the century on Prince Edward Island, Matthew Cuthbert and his
sister Marilla decide to take on an orphan boy as help for their farm.
But they get an unexpected jolt when they're
mistakenly sent a girl instead: Anne Shirley.
Anne Shirley, played by Megan Follows.
Marilla Cuthbert, played by Colleen Dewhurst.
Matthew Cuthbert, played by Richard Farnsworth.
Rachel Lynde, played by Patricia Hamilton.
Miss Muriel Stacey, played by Marilyn Lightstone.
Diana Barry, played by Schuyler Grant.
Anne of Green Gables is a 1985 Canadian made-for-television drama film based on the 1908 novel of the same
name by Canadian author Lucy Maud Montgomery, and is the first in a series of four films.
The film stars Megan Follows in the title role of Anne Shirley and was produced and
directed by Kevin Sullivan for the Canadian Broadcasting Corporation.
It was released theatrically in Iran, Israel, Europe, and Japan.
The film aired on CBC Television as a two-part
mini-series on 1 and 2 December 1985.
Both parts of the film were among the highest-rated programs of any
genre ever to air on a Canadian television network.
On February 17, 1986, the film aired on PBS in the US on the series WonderWorks.
The film achieved high ratings in the United Kingdom
when it aired on New Year’s Day in 1987.
The film explores themes of canada, sibling relationship,
based on novel or book, optimism, village.
The tone is emotional.